Their town, his war.
Stand Your Ground is a action, thriller, crime film directed by Fansu Njie.
Former Special Forces operative, Jack Johnson, uses the Stand Your Ground law to seek vengeance for his wife’s
murder, igniting a brutal war against a local crime lord’s family and ending in an explosive showdown.
Jack Johnson, played by Daniel Stisen.
Bastion, played by Peter Stormare.
Earl, played by Eric Roberts.
Mouse, played by Adam Basil.
Officer Jones, played by Akie Kotabe.
Charles, played by Beau Fowler.
The Perfect Neighbor is a 2025 American documentary film directed by Geeta Gandbhir about the killing of Ajike Owens, a shooting incident on
June 2, 2023 where a white female, Susan Louise Lorincz, fatally shot Owens, her black female neighbor, in Ocala, Florida.
The film is told in chronological order with limited narration, mostly using pre-existing police footage such as bodycams', and follows both the lead-up to the killing, the
incident itself and its aftermath, from the neighborhood disputes eventually escalating into the killing to Lorincz's conviction for manslaughter, among other charges.
As the killing itself did, the film notably questions the systemic bias
in how Florida's stand-your-ground laws are applied.
The film had its world premiere at the 2025 Sundance Film Festival
on January 24, where it won the Directing Award.
It had a limited theatrical release in the U.S.
on October 10, prior to streaming globally on Netflix on October 17.
It received widespread acclaim for its production, direction and editing, and its effective
questioning of the circumstances surrounding Owens' death and similar incidents.
At the 98th Academy Awards, it was nominated for Best Documentary.
The tone is dark and intense.